# **Paul Farcas**

# **Junior Developer**

paulfarcas13@gmail.com Phone number (514) 358-6893

#### **Profile**

2 years experience as developer Computer Science and Software Engineering bachelor's degree Trilingual - English, French and Romanian

Strong communication skills and teamwork abilities Good capacity to prioritize tasks Efficient analytical and problems solving skills Motivated fast learner Responsible, dependable et loyal

### Technical Competences

Languages/Web: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JSON, MySQL, Java, UML, Node.js, Bootstrap

**Tools:** Visual Studio Code, Microsoft Office, Eclipse, NetBeans, WebStorm

**Environments:** Windows

## Professional Experiences

#### **Software Developer - Escalade**

March 2017 - September 2017

NEXSAN, Montréal, Canada

- Develop software to improve support capabilities in the field, such as better diagnostic tools
- Investigate customer issues, analyse logs, replicate results, find solutions and solve problems using Bash scripting
- Perfect product code and fix bugs to improve reliability
- Track escalation indicators and help improve the overall quality of the product
- Participate in and contribute to any other activity that would be beneficial to the company, at the request of the employee's manager or senior management of the company

#### **Junior Programmer**

**June 2015 – August 2016** 

OCIUS, Montréal, Canada

- Create and coordinate the company's website according to customer specifications working with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery
- Develop the user-friendly and adaptive web site using CSS
- Rewrite the code for the features of the website
- Ensure the quality of the code
- Design and maintain a project with Meteor.js
- Analyze and implement the code of the realization of software
- Participate in meetings with the client to know the goals of the project
- Find and fix the application's bugs
- Test and maintain the good functionality of the site and the project
- Install and configure software applications

# **Professional Experiences**

#### Computer technician

May 2012 - December 2012

REVENU QUÉBEC, Montréal, Canada

- Create virtual images using GHOST
- Perform the activities necessary to update and install computer systems
- Perform timely software initializations and reinstallations
- Perform and review scheduled and unplanned backup updates
- Solve various technical problems (software and hardware)
- Advise customers and users on the migration of hardware and software
- Offer technical support and expertise to users regarding the security and maintenance of their IT systems
- Document each intervention, in a relevant way
- Participate in inventory taking
- Ensure the maintenance and evolution of computer networks

# Personal Experiences

#### Job Search Organizer

2020

Web application using React

- Save job searches, using a form, into a database
  - View, modify, update and filter the jobs a user applied for
  - Follow up on the stages of the application process
  - Compatible with all devices

#### **Portfolio**

https://paulf-portfolio.herokuapp.com

## Education

#### Improvement in web developing

2018-2019

# Computer Science and Software Engineering bachelor's degree

2009 - 2014

Université du Québec à Montréal

References upon request